Register of the Library of Social History Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Cuban Revolutionary Government Series, 1931-1992 (Box 200-248)
  - Individual speeches and writings. Printed unless otherwise indicated
    - Remarks, press conference with foreign journalists re invasion of Cuba, 1961 June 14? (Box-folder 203: 22)
      - Remarks, Feria Internacional de La Habana, 1986 November 5 (Box-folder 222: 13)
      - Message to President Raúl Alfonsín of Argentina, 1986 November 7 (Box-folder 222: 14)
      - Remarks, medical congress, 1986 November 25 (Box-folder 222: 15)
      - Remarks re Iran-contra affair, 1986 November 28 (Box-folder 222: 16)
      - Speech and additional remarks, Partido Comunista congress, 1986 November 30-December 2 (Box-folder 222: 17)
      - Remarks, opening of Fundación del Nuevo Cine Latinoamericano, Havana, 1986 December 4 (Box-folder 222: 18)
      - Speech, opening of new film and television school, 1986 December 15 (Box-folder 222: 19)
      - Speech and additional remarks, visit to Bayamo, 1986 December 18-19 (Box-folder 222: 20)
      - Speeches, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1986 December 26-27 (Box-folder 222: 21)
      - Message to Vietnamese leaders, 1986 December (Box-folder 222: 22)
      - Speech, La Habana provincial meeting, Partido Comunista, 1987 January 7 (Box-folder 222: 23)
      - Speeches, Federación Estudiantil Universitaria congress, 1987 January 9 and 10 (Box-folder 222: 24)
      - Speech and additional remarks, Central de Trabajadores meeting, 1987 January 13-14 (Box-folder 222: 25)
      - Remarks, Congreso Latinoamericano de Estudiantes, Havana, 1987 January 15 (Box-folder 222: 26)
      - Remarks, construction projects planning meeting, 1987 January 16 (Box-folder 222: 27)
      - Telephone conversation with President José Sarney of Brazil and subsequent remarks to Brazilian journalists, 1987 January 22-23 (Box-folder 222: 28)
      - Speech and additional remarks, Ministerio de la Industria Básica meeting, 1987 January 30-31 (Box-folder 222: 29)
      - Speech, Seminario Nacional de Educación Media, 1987 February 5 (Box-folder 223: 1)
      - Remarks re drug traffic, 1987 February 23 (Box-folder 223: 2)
      - Remarks re Brazilian debt moratorium, 1987 February 23-28 (Box-folder 223: 3)
      - Remarks, tour of Camagüey province, 1987 March 10-12 (Box-folder 223: 4)
      - Speech, anniversary of presidential palace assault, 1987 March 13 (Box-folder 223: 5)
      - Remarks, opening of new home for elderly, 1987 March 16 (Box-folder 223: 6)
      - Remarks, press conference with Brazilian journalists, 1987 March 18 (Box-folder 223: 7)
      - Remarks, opening of new textile mill, 1987 March 26 (Box-folder 223: 8)
      - Interview with Elio Gaspari ( Veja [Brazil]), 1987 March (Box-folder 223: 9)
      - Interview with Uruguayan television journalists, 1987 March (Box-folder 223: 10)
      - Speech and additional remarks, Unión de Jóvenes Comunistas congress, 1987 April 1-5 (Box-folder 223: 11)
      - Message to Kim Il Sung, 1987 April 14 (Box-folder 223: 12)
      - Message to President Raúl Alfonsín of Argentina, 1987 April 17 (Box-folder 223: 13)
      - Speech, Group of 77 Ministerial Meeting, Havana, 1987 April 20 (Box-folder 223: 14)
      - Speech, memorial service for Blas Roca, 1987 April 26 (Box-folder 223: 15)
      - Speech, medical technology fair, 1987 April 30 (Box-folder 223: 16)
      - Speech and additional remarks, Asamblea Nacional de los Agricultores Pequeños congress, 1987 May 15-17 (Box-folder 223: 17)
      - Remarks re rectification process, Guanabacoa municipal meeting, Partido Comunista, 1987 May 26 (Box-folder 223: 18)
      - Remarks, Diez de Octubre municipal meeting, Partido Comunista, 1987 May 29 (Box-folder 223: 19)
      - Interview with Roland Leroy ( L'humanité [France]), 1987 May. (Box-folder 223: 20)
        French (printed), English (printed)
      - Message to Ministerial Conference of the Non-aligned Countries, 1987 June 9 (Box-folder 223: 21)
      - Remarks, La Habana provincial meeting, Partido Comunista, 1987 June 11 (Box-folder 223: 22)
      - Televised speech re arrest of Luis Orlando Dominguez and defection of Rafael del Pino, 1987 June 24 (Box-folder 223: 23)
      - Remarks re rectification process, enterprise management meetings, 1987 June 25-26 (Box-folder 223: 24)
      - Interview with Gianni Mina ( L'espresso [Italy]), 1987 June 28 (Box-folder 223: 25)
      - Remarks, La Habana provincial meeting, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1987 July 4 (Box-folder 224: 1)
      - Remarks, tour of Pinar del Rio province, 1987 July 6-8 (Box-folder 224: 2)
      - Remarks, Unió n de Periodistas meeting, 1987 July 9 (Box-folder 224: 3)
      - Remarks, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1987 July 16-18 (Box-folder 224: 4)
      - Remarks re rectification process, Comité Central plenum, Partido Comunista, 1987 July 18 (Box-folder 224: 5)
      - Message to President Daniel Ortega Saavedra of Nicaragua, 1987 July 18 (Box-folder 224: 6)
      - Remarks, family doctor program meeting, 1987 July 21 (Box-folder 224: 7)
      - Speech, Moncada anniversary, 1987 July 26 (Box-folder 224: 8)
      - Remarks, meeting on national economy, 1987 August (Box-folder 224: 9)
      - Message re defecting athlete, 1987 August 11 (Box-folder 224: 10)
      - Remarks, Asociación Cubana de Limitados Físico-Motores congress, 1987 August 19 (Box-folder 224: 11)
      - Remarks, beginning of new school year, 1987 September 1 (Box-folder 224: 12)
      - Remarks, opening of new child care center, 1987 September 2 (Box-folder 224: 13)
      - Remarks, meeting on national police, 1987 September 4 (Box-folder 224: 14)
      - Speech, opening of new hospital, 1987 September 5 (Box-folder 224: 15)
      - Speech, opening of new immunology research center, 1987 September 7 (Box-folder 224: 16)
      - Message to International Olympic Committee, 1987 September 11 (Box-folder 224: 17)
      - Remarks re AIDS, 1987 September 14 (Box-folder 224: 18)
      - Speech welcoming Cuban athletes returning from Pan-American Games, 1987 September 16 (Box-folder 224: 19)
      - Speech re human rights, Asociación Americana de Juristas conference, Havana, 1987 September 17 (Box-folder 224: 20)
      - Remarks, Arroyo Naranjo municipal meeting, Partido Comunista, 1987 September 19 (Box-folder 224: 21)
      - Remarks, opening of new child care center, 1987 September 23 (Box-folder 224: 22)
      - Remarks, Central Comité plenum, Partido Comunista, 1987 September 24-25 (Box-folder 224: 23)
      - Remarks, San Miguel del Padrón municipal meeting, Partido Comunista, 1987 September 27 (Box-folder 224: 24)
      - Remarks, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1987 September 28-29 (Box-folder 224: 25)
      - Speech, anniversary of minibrigade movement, 1987 September 30 (Box-folder 224: 26)
      - Remarks, opening of new hospital, 1987 October 8 (Box-folder 224: 27)
      - Speech, anniversary of death of Ernesto Guevara, 1987 October 8 (Box-folder 224: 28)
      - Remarks, Playa municipal meeting, Partido Comunista, 1987 October 11 (Box-folder 224: 29)
      - Remarks, road construction site, 1987 October 28 (Box-folder 224: 30)
      - Remarks, meeting on national economy, 1987 October 30 (Box-folder 224: 31)
      - Interview with Yugoslav journalists, 1987 November (Box-folder 225: 1)
      - Speech, Meeting of Parties and Liberation Movements, Moscow, Russia, 1987 November 6 (Box-folder 225: 2)
      - Remarks, press conference upon return to Cuba from Soviet Union, 1987 November 8 (Box-folder 225: 3)
      - Remarks, opening of new school, 1987 November 10 (Box-folder 225: 4)
      - Remarks to journalists, 1987 November 22 (Box-folder 225: 5)
      - Speech, Pan American Railway Congress Association meeting, Havana, 1987 November 22 (Box-folder 225: 6)
      - Remarks, international students' conference, Havana, 1987 November 23 (Box-folder 225: 7)
      - Remarks, opening of new child care centers, 1987 November 25 (Box-folder 225: 8)
      - Remarks, Latin American and Caribbean Economists Association congress, Havana, 1987 November 26 (Box-folder 225: 9)
      - Speech and additional remarks, La Habana provincial meeting, Partido Comunista, 1987 November 27-29 (Box-folder 225: 10)
      - Speech, opening of new hospital, 1987 December 4 (Box-folder 225: 11)
      - Speech and additional remarks, Federación de Estudiantes de la Enseñanza Media congress, 1987 December 5-7 (Box-folder 225: 12)
      - Message to Latin American presidents, 1987 December 10 (Box-folder 225: 13)
      - Remarks, opening of new child care centers, 1987 December 10 (Box-folder 225: 14)
      - Remarks, visit to hospital, 1987 December 11 (Box-folder 225: 15)
      - Remarks to Brazilian journalists, 1987 December 16 (Box-folder 225: 16)
      - Remarks, Teachers' Day, 1987 December 23 (Box-folder 225: 17)
      - Speech, opening of new aqueduct, 1987 December 24 (Box-folder 225: 18)
      - Remarks, national meeting on water resources, 1987 December 25 (Box-folder 225: 19)
      - Remarks, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1987 December 28-29 (Box-folder 225: 20)
      - Remarks, opening of new child care centers, 1987 December 30 (Box-folder 225: 21)
      - Interview with Patrice Barrat ( Cambio 16 [Spain]), 1987 (Box-folder 225: 22)
      - Message to International Olympic Committee, 1988 January 15 (Box-folder 225: 23)
      - Speech, Unión Nacional de Escritores y Artistas congress, 1988 January 28 (Box-folder 225: 24)
      - Message to Cambodian leaders, 1988 January (Box-folder 225: 25)
      - Remarks, Comité Estatal de Trabajo y Seguridad Social meeting, 1988 February 4 (Box-folder 225: 26)
      - Remarks, Ministerio de la Industria Básica meeting, 1988 February 5 (Box-folder 225: 27)
      - Letter to Sara de Peña, 1988 February 9 (Box-folder 225: 28)
      - Remarks, medical facilities, 1988 February 11 (Box-folder 225: 29)
      - Interview with USA Today journalists, 1988 February 21 (Box-folder 225: 30)
      - Interview with Maria Shriver (NBC), 1988 February 24 (Box-folder 225: 31)
      - Remarks re Panama, press conference with Panamanian television journalists, 1988 February 29 (Box-folder 225: 32)
      - Interview with Fernando Quiñones ( El independiente [Spain]), 1988 February (Box-folder 225: 33)
      - Remarks, Asociació n Hermanos Saíz meeting, 1988 March 12 (Box-folder 225: 34)
      - Remarks presenting awards to Cuban Olympic Games champions, 1988 March 16 (Box-folder 225: 35)
      - Message to Asociació n Cubana de Limitados Físico-Motores meeting, 1988 March 25 (Box-folder 225: 36)
      - Remarks, visit to heart surgery center, 1988 April 2 (Box-folder 225: 37)
      - Remarks, opening of new health facilities, 1988 April 7 (Box-folder 225: 38)
      - Remarks, meeting on construction planning, 1988 April 28 (Box-folder 225: 39)
      - Remarks, opening of new medical emergency center, 1988 April 29 (Box-folder 225: 40)
      - Speech, beginning of new construction projects, 1988 April 30 (Box-folder 225: 41)
      - Remarks, meeting with U.S. religious leaders, 1988 April (Box-folder 225: 42)
      - Interview with Esteban Valenti ( La hora [Uruguay]), 1988 April (Box-folder 225: 43)
      - Remarks upon receiving award from Permanent Congress for the Labor Unity of Latin American and Caribbean Workers, Havana, 1988 May 1 (Box-folder 225: 44)
      - Remarks upon visit of Yemeni delegation, 1988 May 6 (Box-folder 225: 45)
      - Remarks, opening of new child care center, 1988 May 21 (Box-folder 225: 46)
      - Remarks, national meeting of agricultural cooperatives, 1988 May 22 (Box-folder 225: 47)
      - Remarks re development plans for Havana, 1988 May 27 (Box-folder 225: 48)
      - Remarks, Ministerial Conference of the Non-aligned Countries, Havana, 1988 May 31 (Box-folder 225: 49)
        Spanish (typed transcript, printed), English (typed transcript, printed)
      - Televised interview with Alfredo Conde Cid (Galician cultural consul), 1988 June 6 (Box-folder 226: 1)
      - Remarks upon visit of President Najibullah of Afghanistan, 1988 June 11 (Box-folder 226: 2)
      - Remarks to students, 1988 June 16 (Box-folder 226: 3)
      - Speech and additional remarks, beginning of new construction projects, 1988 June 22 (Box-folder 226: 4)
      - Remarks, minibrigade meeting, 1988 June 29 (Box-folder 226: 5)
      - Remarks upon visit of President Daniel Ortega Saavedra of Nicaragua, 1988 June 29 (Box-folder 226: 6)
      - Speech and additional remarks, Sindicato Nacional de Trabajadores de la Construcció n congress, 1988 July 5-6 (Box-folder 226: 7)
      - Speech and additional remarks, enterprise management meeting, 1988 July 7-8 (Box-folder 226: 8)
      - Remarks, opening of new library facility, 1988 July 18 (Box-folder 226: 9)
      - Message to Nelson Mandela, 1988 July 18 (Box-folder 226: 10)
      - Message to Nicaraguan leaders, 1988 July 18 (Box-folder 226: 11)
      - Remarks, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1988 July 18-19 (Box-folder 226: 12)
      - Remarks, visit to Granma province, 1988 July 22 (Box-folder 226: 13)
      - Remarks, opening of new hospital, 1988 July 22 (Box-folder 226: 14)
      - Remarks, opening of new oil refinery, 1988 July 24 (Box-folder 226: 15)
      - Speech, Moncada anniversary, 1988 July 26 (Box-folder 226: 16)
        Spanish (printed), English (printed), French (printed)
      - Remarks, promotion of Ministerio del Interior officials, 1988 July 26 (Box-folder 226: 17)
      - Remarks, Quito, Ecuador, 1988 August 9 (Box-folder 226: 18)
      - Remarks, Quito, Ecuador, 1988 August 12 (Box-folder 226: 19)
      - Remarks, press conference, Quito, Ecuador, 1988 August 13 (Box-folder 226: 20)
      - Speech to graduating physicians, 1988 September 1 (Box-folder 226: 21)
      - Remarks welcoming return of Cuban baseball team from international competition, 1988 September 10 (Box-folder 226: 22)
      - Remarks during tour of hurricane damage, 1988 September 14 (Box-folder 226: 23)
      - Speech presenting awards to athletes, 1988 September 22 (Box-folder 226: 24)
      - Message to international conference on debt, 1988 September 23 (Box-folder 226: 25)
        Spanish (typed transcript), English (typed transcript)
      - Remarks, meeting on tourism development, 1988 September 26 (Box-folder 226: 26)
      - Speech to bus workers, 1988 October 3 (Box-folder 226: 27)
      - Speech, opening of new facilities, 1988 October 5 (Box-folder 226: 28)
      - Speech and additional remarks, opening of new facilities, 1988 October 6 (Box-folder 226: 29)
      - Speech and additional remarks, Continental Women's Meeting, Havana, 1988 October 6-7 (Box-folder 226: 30)
      - Interview with Altaf Gauhar ( South), 1988 October 9 (Box-folder 226: 31)
      - Speech and additional remarks, opening of new medical facility, 1988 October 28 (Box-folder 226: 32)
      - Speech upon receiving Aztec Eagle Order award from President Miguel de la Madrid of Mexico, Havana, 1988 November 1 (Box-folder 227: 1)
      - Remarks, visit to Feria Internacional de La Habana, 1988 November 6 (Box-folder 227: 2)
      - Remarks, meeting of architects of socialist countries, Havana, 1988 November 13 (Box-folder 227: 3)
      - Speech, opening of new medical facility, 1988 November 15 (Box-folder 227: 4)
      - Remarks, International Seminar on Primary Health Care, Havana, 1988 November 16-17 (Box-folder 227: 5)
      - Speech, opening of new arms plant, 1988 November 27 (Box-folder 227: 6)
      - Speech, opening of new rolling mill, 1988 November 28 (Box-folder 227: 7)
      - Speech, anniversary of Battle of Guisa, 1988 November 29 (Box-folder 227: 8)
      - Remarks during visit to Mexico, 1988 December 2 (Box-folder 227: 9)
      - Remarks, press conference, Mexico, Mexico, 1988 December 3 (Box-folder 227: 10)
      - Speech, Tuxpan, Mexico, 1988 December 4 (Box-folder 227: 11)
      - Message to President Raúl Alfonsín of Argentina, 1988 December 4 (Box-folder 227: 12)
      - Remarks, press conference upon return to Cuba from visit to Mexico, 1988 December 4 (Box-folder 227: 13)
      - Speech, anniversary of Granma landing, 1988 December 5 (Box-folder 227: 14)
      - Message to Mikhail Gorbachev and subsequent statements re Cuban aid to Soviet Union after earthquake in Armenia, 1988 December 8-12 (Box-folder 227: 15)
      - Remarks re manufacture of buses, 1988 December 21 (Box-folder 227: 16)
      - Speeches, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1988 December 22-23 (Box-folder 227: 17)
      - Remarks re Namibia, 1988 December 25 (Box-folder 227: 18)
      - Speech, opening of new medical facility, 1988 December 30 (Box-folder 227: 19)
      - Speech, anniversary of Cuban Revolution, 1989 January 1 (Box-folder 227: 20)
      - Speech re anniversary of Cuban Revolution, 1989 January 4 (Box-folder 227: 21)
      - Remarks upon receipt of Eduardo Mondlane Medal from Mozambique, Havana, 1989 January 6 (Box-folder 227: 22)
      - Speech, anniversary of revolutionary entrance into Havana, 1989 January 8 (Box-folder 227: 23)
      - Remarks re Pope John Paul II, 1989 January 19 (Box-folder 227: 24)
      - Interview with El nacional (Venezuela), 1989 January 21 (Box-folder 227: 25)
      - Remarks, meeting with Latin American jurists, 1989 January 25 (Box-folder 227: 26)
      - Interview with Lowell Blankfort (National Council on U.S.-Cuban Relations), 1989 January 26 (Box-folder 227: 27)
      - Speech, opening of new child care centers, 1989 January 28 (Box-folder 227: 28)
      - Speeches, schools for Namibian and North Korean students in Cuba, 1989 January 29 (Box-folder 227: 29)
        Spanish (mimeograph, printed), English (printed)
      - Remarks to journalists, Caracas, Venezuela, 1989 February 2-3 (Box-folder 227: 30)
      - Interview with Nelson Bucaranda, Caracas, Venezuela, 1989 February 3 (Box-folder 227: 31)
      - Remarks to journalists, Caracas, Venezuela, 1989 February 4 (Box-folder 227: 32)
      - Remarks, meeting with intellectuals, Caracas, Venezuela, 1989 February 4 (Box-folder 227: 33)
      - Remarks, televised press conference, Caracas, Venezuela, 1989 February 4 (Box-folder 227: 34)
      - Interview with Mayra Clavijo (Ecuadoran journalist), 1989 February 12 (Box-folder 227: 35)
      - Speech and additional remarks, national seminar on education, 1989 February 18 (Box-folder 227: 36)
      - Remarks upon receiving Great Cross of the Order of Mali, Havana, 1989 February 21 (Box-folder 227: 37)
      - Remarks, Ministerio de la Industria Básica meeting, 1989 February 23 (Box-folder 227: 38)
      - Speech, opening of new neurological center, 1989 February 26 (Box-folder 227: 39)
      - Message to Romanian leaders, 1989 February 26 (Box-folder 227: 40)
      - Remarks, Ministerio del Interior meeting, 1989 March 3 (Box-folder 228: 1)
      - Remarks, tour of Pinar del Rio province, 1989 March 11 (Box-folder 228: 2)
      - Remarks re human rights, 1989 March 12 (Box-folder 228: 3)
      - Remarks re oil research, 1989 March 13 (Box-folder 228: 4)
      - Remarks, meeting on medical research, 1989 March 17 (Box-folder 228: 5)
      - Speech, anniversary of state security forces, 1989 March 26 (Box-folder 228: 6)
      - Message to Mikhail Gorbachev, 1989 March 31 (Box-folder 228: 7)
      - Interview with Monica Riedler (Austrian journalist), 1989 April 1 (Box-folder 228: 8)
      - Remarks upon visit of Mikhail Gorbachev, 1989 April 2 (Box-folder 228: 9)
      - Speech upon visit of Mikhail Gorbachev and Soviet delegation, 1989 April 4 (Box-folder 228: 10)
      - Remarks, joint press conference with Mikhail Gorbachev, 1989 April 4 (Box-folder 228: 11)
      - Remarks re visit of Mikhail Gorbachev, 1989 April 5 (Box-folder 228: 12)
      - Remarks, visit to agroindustrial center, 1989 April 11 (Box-folder 228: 13)
      - Remarks, visit to highway concstruction site, 1989 April 18 (Box-folder 228: 14)
      - Remarks, tour of Pinar del Rio province, 1989 April 27 (Box-folder 228: 15)
      - Remarks, visit to health fair, 1989 April 28 (Box-folder 228: 16)
      - Remarks upon visit of Nguyen Van Linh and Vietnamese delegation, 1989 April 30 (Box-folder 228: 17)
      - Remarks re elections, 1989 April 30 (Box-folder 228: 18)
      - Interview with Zdeněk Hoření (Czech journalist), 1989 April (Box-folder 228: 19)
      - Speech, medical school, 1989 May 5 (Box-folder 228: 20)
      - Speech, Sancti Spíritus, 1989 May 6 (Box-folder 228: 21)
      - Remarks, tour of Matanzas province, 1989 May 9 (Box-folder 228: 22)
      - Remarks, anniversary of Agencia de Información Nacional, 1989 May 20 (Box-folder 228: 23)
      - Remarks, Federació n de Estudiantes de la Enseñanza Media congress, 1989 May 25 (Box-folder 228: 24)
      - Speech, anniversary of agricultural enterprise, 1989 May 26 (Box-folder 228: 25)
      - Message to Mikhail Gorbachev, 1989 May 26 (Box-folder 228: 26)
      - Remarks, opening of new obstetric facility, 1989 May 29 (Box-folder 228: 27)
      - Remarks, formation of new work brigades, 1989 May 31 (Box-folder 228: 28)
      - Speech, opening of new medical facilities, 1989 June 5 (Box-folder 228: 29)
      - Remarks, beginning of new construction project, 1989 June 6 (Box-folder 228: 30)
      - Message to Mikhail Gorbachev, 1989 June 6 (Box-folder 228: 31)
      - Message to President José Eduardo dos Santos of Angola, 1989 June 25 (Box-folder 228: 32)
      - Message to World Festival of Youth and Students, 1989 June 27 (Box-folder 228: 33)
      - Televised speech re trial of General Arnaldo Ochoa, 1989 July 9 (Box-folder 228: 34)
      - Remarks, Asamblea Nacional del Poder Popular, 1989 July 17-18 (Box-folder 228: 35)
      - Speech, opening of new health facilities, 1989 July 19 (Box-folder 228: 36)
      - Message to President Daniel Ortega Saavedra of Nicaragua, 1989 July 19 (Box-folder 228: 37)
      - Speech, Moncada anniversary, 1989 July 26 (Box-folder 228: 38)
      - Message to United Nations re Angola, 1989 August 16 (Box-folder 228: 39)
      - Speech, beginning of new school year, 1989 September 4 (Box-folder 228: 40)
      - Speech, ceremony in solidarity with Chile, 1989 September 11 (Box-folder 228: 41)
      - Speech, opening of new medical facilities, 1989 September 11 (Box-folder 228: 42)
      - Remarks, meeting on reorganization of Ministerio del Interior, 1989 September 24 (Box-folder 228: 43)
      - Speech, opening of new airport, 1989 September 25 (Box-folder 228: 44)
      - Speech, anniversary of minibrigade movement, 1989 September 30 (Box-folder 228: 45)
      - Speech re work brigades, 1989 October 1 (Box-folder 228: 46)
      - Remark, joint press conference with Jaime Wheelock (Nicaragua), 1989 October 1 (Box-folder 228: 47)
      - Speech, opening of new botanical garden, 1989 October 26 (Box-folder 228: 48)
      - Televised interview with Venezuelan journalists, 1989 October 26 (Box-folder 228: 49)
      - Speech, anniversary of disappearance of Camilo Cienfuegos, 1989 October 28 (Box-folder 228: 50)
      - Remarks to telephone workers, 1989 October 31 (Box-folder 228: 51)
      - Message to President Francisco Rodríguez Poveda of Panama, 1989 November 3 (Box-folder 229: 1)
      - Speech, opening of new construction material plant, 1989 November 7 (Box-folder 229: 2)
      - Remarks to journalists, 1989 November 15 (Box-folder 229: 3)
      - Message to Sam Nujoma (South West African Peoples Organisation), 1989 November 15 (Box-folder 229: 4)
      - Remarks, meeting on heavy industry, 1989 November 21 (Box-folder 229: 5)
      - Speech, opening of new hospital, 1989 November 30 (Box-folder 229: 6)
      - Speech, memorial service for Cubans killed in Angola, 1989 December 7 (Box-folder 229: 7)
      - Remarks, meeting of Partido Comunista leaders, 1989 December 11-13 (Box-folder 229: 8)